Guide to the Paul A. Samuelson papers, 1933-2010 and undated RL.10082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1935-2010 and undated, 79 boxes
  - Correspondence with individuals and organizations, 1935-2010 and undated, 70 boxes
    - Mongiovi, Gary, 1993-2005 (Box 54)
    - Monte dei Paschi di Siena, 1989-1994 (Box 54)
    - Moore, Geoffrey H., 1972-1974 (Box 54)
    - Morgenstern, Oskar, 1949-1977 (Box 54)
    - Morishima, Michio, 1964-1997 (Box 54)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1972-1991 (Box 54)
    - Musgrave, Richard, 1945-2007 (Box 54)
    - Muskie, Edmund S. (Maine Senator), 1971-1978 (Box 54)
    - Myers, Charles, 1951-2000 (Box 54)
    - General Correspondence: N, 1942-2009, 1-3 of 5 folders (Box 54)
    - General Correspondence: N, 1942-2009, 4-5 of 5 folders (Box 55)
    - Nasar, Sylvia, 1994-2006 (Box 55)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1946-1987 (Box 55)
    - National Research Council, 1979-1988 (Box 55)
    - National Resources Planning Board, 1941-1943 (Box 55)
    - National Science Foundation, 1975-1991 (Box 55)
    - Negishi, Takashi, 1989-1994 (Box 55)
    - Neisser, Haus, 1942-1968 (Box 55)
    - Nell, E. (New School), 1973-1991 (Box 56)
    - New Republic, 1944-1949 (Box 56)
    - Newsweek, 1960-2005 (Box 56)
    - New York Times Letter to the Editor (not sent), 1961 (Box 56)
    - Niehans, Jurg, 1990-2005 (Box 56)
    - Nihon, Keizai Shimbun, 1962-2008 (Box 56)
    - Nordhaus, William, 1972-2009 (Box 56)
    - Nueno, Pedro, 2003-2009 (Box 56)
    - General Correspondence: O, 1945-2009, 1 of 2 folders (Box 56)
    - General Correspondence: O, 1945-2009, 2 of 2 folders (Box 57)
    - O'Brien, Denis, 1991-2006 (Box 57)
    - O'Connell, Joan, 1992-1996 (Box 57)
    - Ohlin, Bertil, 1947-1979 (Box 57)
    - The Oslo Group, 1980-1982 (Box 57)
    - Oxford Economic Papers, 1966-2007 (Box 57)
    - Owen, Lyle (U. of Tulsa, retirement party), 1972-1973 (Box 57)
    - General Correspondence: P, 1940-2009, 1-3 of 6 folders (Box 57)
    - General Correspondence: P, 1940-2009, 4-6 of 6 folders (Box 58)
    - Panico, Carlo, 1989-1992 (Box 58)
    - Papandreou, Andreas, 1949-1997 (Box 58)
    - Pappas, Jill, 1982-2005 (Box 58)
    - Pasinetti, Luigi, 1958-2005 (Box 58)
    - Patinkin, Don (The Hebrew University), 1946-1995, 1 of 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Patinkin, Don (The Hebrew University), 1946-1995, 2-3 of 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Patman Testimony, 1952-1954 (Box 59)
    - Pearce, Ivor, 1951-1977 (Box 59)
    - Pechman, Joseph, 1957-1992 (Box 59)
    - Perlman, Mark, 1969-2006 (Box 59)
    - Phelps, Ned (U. of Pennsylvania), 1960-2008 (Box 59)
    - Pollack, Robert, 1962-2005 (Box 60)
    - Pope, Robin, 1983-2007 (Box 60)
    - Poterba, James, 1992-2008 (Box 60)
    - Pratt, John, 1968-2006 (Box 60)
    - Princeton University Press, 1977-2001 (Box 60)
    - Proxmire, William, 1974-1979 (Box 60)
    - Publishers, 1944-1949 (Box 60)
    - Puerto Rico, 1946-1996 (Box 60)
    - On Purcell and personal probability, 1962 (Box 60)
    - General Correspondence: Q, 1944-2001 (Box 60)
    - Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1945-1989 (Box 60)
    - General Correspondence: R, 1946-2009, 1-2 of 7 folders (Box 60)
    - General Correspondence: R, 1946-2009, 3-7 of 7 folders (Box 61)
    - Radiation Lab, 1944-1945 (Box 61)
    - Radical Economics, 1969-1970 (Box 61)
    - Ramachandran, Rama, 1987-2005 (Box 62)
    - Rand Corporation, 1949-1988, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - Rand Corporation contracts, 1948-1984 (Box 62)
    - Recktenwald, Horst, 1963-1989 (Box 62)
    - Refereeing of papers, 1968-1969 (Box 62)
    - Reuss, Henry S. (congressman), 1961-1975 (Box 62)
    - Review of Economic Studies, 1947-1951 (Box 62)
    - Review of Economics and Statistics, 1942-1969 and undated (Box 62)
    - Richter, Marcel, 1958-2007 (Box 62)
    - Richter, Rudolf, 1956-1990 (Box 63)
    - Richter, Wolfram, 1987 (Box 63)
    - Riley, John, 1983-1986 (Box 63)
    - Robbins, Lionel, 1948-1984 (Box 63)
    - Robertson, Dennis, 1945-1993 (Box 63)
    - Robinson, E. Austin G. (I.E.A. Marshall Library, Cambridge, England), 1948-1989 (Box 63)
    - Robinson, Joan, 1958-1988, 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Robinson, Romney, 1955-1973 (Box 63)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-2008 (Box 63)
    - Roll, Sir Eric, 1947-2005 (Box 63)
    - Roosa, Robert V., 1944-1964 (Box 63)
    - Roskamp, Karl, 1980-2006 (Box 63)
    - Rosovsky, Henry, 1960-1994 and undated (Box 63)
    - Ross, Stephen, 1977-1997 (Box 63)
    - Rostow, Walt, 1968-2007 (Box 63)
    - Ruggles, Richard, 1948-1965 (Box 63)
    - Russell, Thomas, 1984-2009, 1 of 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Russell, Thomas, 1984-2009, 2 of 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Russian scientists, 1972-1985 (Box 64)
    - Rutgers University, 12-13 May 1971 (Box 64)
    - General Correspondence: S, 1939-2009, 1-4 of 17 folders (Box 64)
    - General Correspondence: S, 1939-2009, 5-11 of 17 folders (Box 65)
    - General Correspondence: S, 1939-2009, 12-16 of 17 folders (Box 66)
    - General Correspondence: S, 1939-2009, 17 of 17 folders (Box 67)
    - Salant, Walter, 1940-2004 (Box 67)
    - Samuels, Warren J. (Journal of Economic Issues), 1974-2008 (Box 67)
    - Sandilands, Roger, 1987-2003 (Box 67)
    - Sato, Ryuzo, 1974-2009, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Savage, Jimmie, 1950-1987 (Box 67)
    - Scarf, Herb, 1977-1995 (Box 68)
    - Schefold, Bertram, 1983-2007 (Box 68)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur Jr., 1950-2001 (Box 68)
    - Schultz, Theodore W., 1946-1998 (Box 68)
    - Schumpeter, Joseph, 1937-2007 (Box 68)
    - Schumpeter Society, 1986-1987 (Box 68)
    - Business Scope, 1957-1961 (Box 68)
    - Scudder, Stevens and Clark (M. Louise Curley), May 5, 1977 (Box 68)
    - Sea Island Georgia Southern Company, 1983 (Box 68)
    - Seiver, Daniel (Pad System Report), 1990-1991 (Box 68)
    - Sen, Amartya, 1963-2007 (Box 68)
    - Seton, Francis, 1971-1989 (Box 68)
    - Shell, Karl, 1966-2003 (Box 68)
    - Sheshinski, Eytan, 1974-2007 (Box 68)
    - Shieh, Yeung-nan, 1983 (Box 68)
    - Shiller, Robert, 1978-2009 (Box 69)
    - Shleifer, Andrei, 2004-2007 (Box 69)
    - Shultz, George P., 1958-2008 (Box 69)
    - Siegel, Jeremy, 1972-1998 (Box 69)
    - Simon, Herbert, 1951-2001 (Box 69)
    - Singh, Narindar, 1990-1993 (Box 69)
    - Skousen, Mark, 1992-2003 (Box 69)
    - Slichter, Sumner, 1947-1949 (Box 69)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1964-2008 (Box 69)
    - Sloan School, 1984-2006 (Box 69)
    - Social Science Quotations (David Sills and Robert K. Merton, Eds.), 1987-1989 (Box 69)
    - Society of Fellows, 1944-1994 (Box 69)
    - Sohmen, Egon, 1957-1992 (Box 69)
    - Solomon, Elinor H., 1990-1998 (Box 70)
    - Solow, Robert M., 1946-2007 (Box 70)
    - Sonnenschein, Hugo, 1969-1998 (Box 70)
    - Soros, George, 1997-1998 (Box 70)
    - Sosin, Howard, 1980 (Box 70)
    - South America, 1958-1963 (Box 70)
    - Southern Economic Journal, 1983-1986 (Box 70)
    - Spain, 1957-1996 (Box 70)
    - Sprinkel, Beryl W. (Harris Trust, Chicago), 1968-1971 (Box 70)
    - Sraffa, Piero, 1948-2005 (Box 70)
    - Srole, Saul, 1977-2007 (Box 70)
    - SST (supersonic transport), 1970 (Box 70)
    - Standard Oil Company, 1952-1957 (Box 70)
    - Steedman, Ian, 1973-2007 (Box 70)
    - Stein, Herbert, 1955-1999 (Box 70)
    - Stevenson, Adlai, 1955-1956 (Box 70)
    - Stigler, George, 1946-1991 (Box 70)
    - Stigler, Stephen, 1987-2010 (Box 71)
    - Stiglitz, Joseph, 1964-2009 (Box 71)
    - Stockfisch, J.A (partial equilibrium concepts) (Box 71)
    - Stolper, Wolfgang A., 1941-2002, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Stone, Richard, 1946-1993 (Box 71)
    - Straub, Dieter, 1993 (Box 71)
    - Streeten, Paul, 1948-2004 (Box 71)
    - Strehle, Glenn, 1981-2005 (Box 71)
    - Summers family, 1948-2003 (Box 71)
    - Summers, Lawrence, 1988-2008 (Box 71)
    - Swamy, Subramanian, 1965-2003 (Box 71)
    - Swedberg, Richard, 1986-2005 (Box 72)
    - Sweeden, 1960-1971 (Box 72)
    - Sweezy, Paul, 1943-1973 (Box 72)
    - Szenberg, Michael, 1989-2006 (Box 72)
    - Szumski, Jerzy, 1986 (Box 72)
    - General Correspondence: T, 1938-2009, 1-3 of 4 folders (Box 72)
    - General Correspondence: T, 1938-2009, 4 of 4 folders (Box 73)
    - Takayama, Akira, 1971-1994 (Box 73)
    - Tinbergen, Jan., 1939-1994 (Box 73)
    - Tobin, James, 1944-2005 (Box 73)
    - Treasury, U.S. Department of, 1944-1975 (Box 73)
    - Trinity University (6 February 1985), 1983-1989 (Box 73)
    - Truesdell, Clifford, 1952-1992 (Box 73)
    - Tsiang, Dr. S.C., 1971-1990 (Box 73)
    - Tsuru, Shigeto, 1947-2006 (Box 73)
    - Tullock, Gordon, 1967-1994 (Box 73)
    - General Correspondence: U, 1943-2008 (Box 74)
    - Uniform Consumer Credit Code (UCCC), 1969 (Box 74)
    - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1976-1994 (Box 74)
    - United States Steel Corporation, 1965-1968 (Box 74)
    - Uzawa, Hirofumi, 1957-1994 (Box 74)
    - General Correspondence: V, 1944-2009, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Val'tukh, Konstantin, 1979-1989 (Box 74)
    - Vandermeulen, Dan, 1946-1997 (Box 74)
    - Vanek, Jaroslav, 1961-1966 (Box 74)
    - Varian, Hal, 1972-2003 (Box 74)
    - Viner, Jacob, 1935-1990 (Box 74)
    - Viscusi, Kip, 1993-2007 (Box 74)
    - Vogt, Arthur, 1977-1989 (Box 75)
    - Vogue (economics of gambling), 1967-1968 (Box 75)
    - Von Weizsacker, Carl C., 1963-2009 (Box 75)
    - DeVries, Margaret, 1944-2005 (Box 75)
    - General Correspondence: W, 1942-2009, 1-5 of 7 folders (Box 75)
    - General Correspondence: W, 1942-2009, 6-7 of 7 folders (Box 76)
    - Wakker, Peter, 1992-1996 (Box 76)
    - Walker, Donald, 1960-2009, 2 folders (Box 76)
    - Wan, Henry, 1961-2003 (Box 76)
    - U.S. War Production Board, 1943-1946 (Box 76)
    - Warsh, David, 1993-2009 (Box 76)
    - Warterman, Anthony M.C., 1992-2010, 2 folders (Box 77)
    - Weintraub, Sidney, 1954-1966 (Box 77)
    - Weitzman, Martin, 1972-2003 (Box 77)
    - Wertheimer, Robert G., 1975-1982 (Box 77)
    - West Point (department of social sciences), 1952-1988 (Box 77)
    - Westfield, Fred, 1953-1979 (Box 77)
    - Weymar, F. Helmut, 1968-1996 (Box 77)
    - John Wiley and Sons, 1950-2004 (Box 77)
    - Williams, John Burr, 1959-1961 (Box 77)
    - Wilson, Edwin B., 1938-1963 (Box 77)
    - Wilson, Edward O., 1975-1993 (Box 77)
    - Wold, Herman, 1952-1962 (Box 77)
    - Wolfson, Martin (Brooklyn, NY), 1947-1984 (Box 77)
    - Wolfson, Murray, 1972-1975 (Box 78)
    - Women (the economics of sex discrimination), 1973 (Box 78)
    - Wong, Stanley (F-Twist and methodology), 1973-1975 (Box 78)
    - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1964-1971 (Box 78)
    - Holbrook Working, 1953-1977 (Box 78)
    - World, United Nations, 1953-1954 (Box 78)
    - Worswick, David, 1948-1987 (Box 78)
    - Wright, David M., 1941-1967, 2 folders (Box 78)
    - General Correspondence: Y, 1942-2008 (Box 78)
    - Yee, Herbert, 1986-1996 (Box 78)
    - Yellin, Joel, 1974-2009, 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Ying, Charles, 1958-1974 (Box 79)
    - General Correspondence: Z, 1947-2008 (Box 79)
    - Zeckhauser, Richard, 1986-2006 (Box 79)
    - Zuckerman, Irving, 1980-1998 (Box 79)
  - Correspondence Related to Textbooks and Other Publications, 1947-2003, 9 boxes
    Chiefly correspondence with McGraw-Hill Publishing Company, particularly regarding editions of Economics and Readings in Economics. This smaller subseries contains correspondence related to Samuelson's textbooks: Economics, Foundations of Economic Analysis and some notes and fragments that were found inside these books. Also includes some materials about other books including the Collected Scientific Papers of Paul A. Samuelson, and Linear Programming and Economic Analysis.
    - Collected Scientific Papers of Paul A. Samuelson
      - MIT Press correspondence, 1963-2010 (Box 79)
      - Reviews, 1965-1970 (Box 79)
    - Economics, 1946-2008, 2 folders
      - Mike Elia's sales reports, 1971-1973 (Box 80)
      - Newsletter, McGraw-Hill, 1969-1983 (Box 80)
      - Samuelson/Scott User comments, 1977 (Box 80)
      - Reprint requests, 1975 (Box 80)
      - Promotion, 1970-1975, 1-3 of 3 folders (Box 80)
      - Criticisms of the textbook, 1947-1997, 2 folders (Box 80)
      - New York Times book review: Speaking of Books: Samuelson's 'Economics,' by Bennett Kremen, 1970 (Box 81)
      - New York Times, 'Economics' Samuelson 8th Edition, 1970 (Box 81)
      - Commentary on Economics, 1966-1967 (Box 81)
      - Translations, 1969-1972 (Box 81)
      - Australian edition, 1967-1968 (Box 81)
      - Canadian Edition, 1968-1969 (Box 81)
      - Japanese translation, 1970 (Box 81)
      - 7th Edition, McGraw-Hill correspondence and corrections, 1963-1969 (1-3 of 3 folders) (Box 81)
      - 8th Edition, 1967-1969 (Box 81)
      - 8th Edition, 1971 (Box 81)
      - 8th Edition, comments (Levine), reviews and correspondence, 1968-1969 (3 folders) (Box 81)
      - Newsletters, 1969-1974 (Box 81)
      - unspecified (Box 81)
      - McGraw-Hill international contracts, 1962-2003 (Box 81)
      - Textbook jobs, 1956 (Box 81)
      - McGraw-Hill, International Division, 1956-1968 (Box 81)
      - Instructor's Manual, 1951 (Box 81)
      - Foreign editions, 1973-1975 (Box 81)
    - Economics (9th edition)
      - Mike Elia: Reviews, 1971-1974 (1-3 of 3 folders) (Box 82)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 82)
      - 9th Edition, review (redoubtable Samuelson), 1973 (Box 82)
      - Sales reports, 1974-1975 (Box 82)
      - Samuelson's comments on samples, 1972 (Box 82)
      - Design dialogue, 1972 (Box 82)
      - Competing texts, 1971-1972 (Box 82)
      - Marketing, 1973 (Box 82)
      - Filmstrip, 1976 (Box 82)
      - Hungarian, 1977 (Box 82)
      - Reviews, reader comments, criticisms, 1975 (10th edition) (Box 82)
    - Economics (10th edition)
      - Miscellaneous draft corrections, 1975 (Box 83)
      - Test Bank and Instructor's Manual, 1976 (Box 83)
      - McGraw-Hill correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 83)
      - Sales reports, 1976-1977 (Box 83)
      - Proofs, design, color, 1975 (Box 83)
      - Ads, undated (Box 83)
      - Newsletter, 1974-1975 (Box 83)
      - Front page, undated (Box 83)
      - German translation, 1976 (Box 83)
      - Preface, 1975 (Box 83)
      - Gallery proofs and photocopies: Chapters 1-3, 5, 7, 1-5 of 22 folders (Box 83)
      - Gallery proofs and photocopies: Chapters 15, 17, 19, 21, 24, 28, 33, 34, 36-42 (6-20 0f 22 folders) (Box 84)
      - Gallery proofs and photocopies: Chapter 43 and Part 6 (21-22 of 22 folders) (Box 85)
      - Reviews, 1981-1982 (Box 85)
    - Foundations of Economic Analysis
      - Correspondence, 1948-1984 (Box 85)
      - Translations, 1970 (Box 85)
      - Errors/errata, 1948-1966 (2 folders) (Box 85)
      - French translation, Gaudot, 1964 (Box 85)
      - Paperback, 1950-1963 (Box 85)
      - Possible preface for Vol. 2 (handwritten), 1965 (Box 85)
      - New foreword for 2nd edition, undated (Box 85)
      - Foreword - unpublished, undated (Box 85)
      - Foreword to Foundations, 2nd edition (Box 85)
      - Harvard University Press translation (Chinese), 1955-2008 (Box 85)
    - Linear Programming and Economic Analysis
      - Samuelson, Dorfman and Solow, 1950-1962, 2 folders (Box 85)
      - McGraw-Hill agreement Skidmore/Samuelson, 1970 (Box 85)
    - Readings in Economics
      - Permission letters and forms, 1973-1974 (Box 85)
      - McGraw-Hill, 1951 (Box 85)
      - McGraw-Hill's ideas about Readings, 1969 (Box 85)
      - Questionnaire, 1968-1969 (Box 85)
      - Xerox of Readings selections, undated (Box 85)
      - McGraw-Hill: testbook school adoptions (Box 85)
    - Readings in Economics, cont.
      - Proofs and corrections, 1955 (Box 86)
      - 1st edition permissions, 1951-1952 (Box 86)
      - 2nd edition permissions, 1955 (Box 86)
      - Revisions, 1952-1971 (Box 86)
    - Other Files
      - American Economic Association, 1949-2007, 1-5 of 6 folders (Box 86)
      - American Economic Association, 1949-2007, 6 of 6 folders (Box 87)
      - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1984-2008 (Box 87)
      - MIT Archive photocopies, 3 folders (Box 87)
      - MIT Press (Box 87)
      - Promotion of McGraw-Hill's other texts, 1974 (Box 87)
      - M-H Modern Social Science (edition) (Box 87)
      - McGraw-Hill Spencer-McConnell plagiarism case, 1971 (Box 87)
      - Translations (Box 87)
      - Visual Learning Corporation, 1969-1972 (Box 87)
- Printed Materials Series, 1930s-2010, 21 boxes
  Contains a near-complete collection of Samuelson's published writings, chiefly in article form. Arranged in three subseries: Articles (published in magazines and newspapers), Books, and Publications. The latter is arranged in the original order maintained by Samuelson. A complete bibliography of his publications, including Newsweek articles, is available in the Special Collections Library and is keyword-searchable; however, some titles listed may not be present in the collection. Contact Research Services for assistance in using this series.
  - Articles Subseries, 1966-1981, 3 boxes
    Includes original and photocopied articles written by Samuelson (and translated into Portuguese) for Homen, a Brazilian magazine; as well as articles for Newsweek, a regular column that he shared with economists Milton Friedman and Henry Wallich. Some folders also include reader feedback or other items.
    The list of Samuelson's Newsweek columns titles and dates of publication is available in Duke's Special Collections Library and is keyword searchable. Consult the Newsweek List to learn which titles are available. Contact Research Services for assistance in using this subseries.
    - Homen articles, 1975-1977 (Box 88)
      - The World Recession Ends, 1975 Aug. (Box 88)
      - Is World Economic Growth at an End?, 1975 Sept. (Box 88)
      - Economic Inequality, 1975 Oct. (Box 88)
      - International Finance Carries On, 1975 Nov. (Box 88)
      - Christmas Economics, 1975 Dec. (Box 88)
      - The Mystique of Gold, 1976 Jan. (Box 88)
      - Sex and Economics, 1976 Feb. (Box 88)
      - On Income Tax, 1976 Mar. (Box 88)
      - How to Invest Your Money, 1976 Apr. (Box 88)
      - International Crisis?, 1976 May (Box 88)
      - America After 5 Centuries, Special Issue, 1976 May (Box 88)
      - State Economic Controls: Myths and Realities, 1976 Oct. (Box 88)
      - Challenges for America's Next President, 1976 Nov. (Box 88)
      - Which is the Enemy: Inflation or Stagnation?, 1977 June (Box 88)
    - Newsweek correspondence, 1966-1979 (Box 88)
    - Mail commentary, 1966-1975 (Box 88)
    - Unpublished articles, 1972-1979 (Box 88)
    - Publications list, 1966-1981 (Box 88)
    - Newsweek articles, 1966-1971(1-51 of 98 folders) (Box 88)
    - Newsweek articles, 1966-1971(52-98 of 98 folders) (Box 89)
    - Newsweek articles, 1972-1977 (1-63 of 110 folders) (Box 89)
    - Newsweek articles, 1966-1977(64-110 of 110 folders) (Box 90)
    - Newsweek articles, 1978-1981 (62 folders) (Box 90)
  - Books Subseries, 1940-1983, 2 boxes
    Contains versions of some of Samuelson's published books; includes a copy of his Ph.D. dissertation and some early personal editions of his textbooks with his notations. Arranged chronologically. Also included are inserts originally laid into copies of his textbooks.
    - Foundations of Analytical Economics: The Observational Significance of Economic Theory, 1940 (Box 91)
    - Modern Economics: An Introductory Analysis of National Income and Policy, 1945 (Box 91)
    - Economics: An Introductory Analysis, (Ph.D. dissertation) 2nd preliminary edition, 1946 (Box 91)
    - Foundations of Economic Analysis, enlarged edition, 1983 (Box 91)
    - Foundations of Economic Analysis, 1947 (Box 91)
    - Inserts/Notes found in copy of Foundations of Economics Analysis, 1947 (Box 91)
    - Inserts/Notes found in copy of Foundations of Economics Analysis, 1983 (Box 91)
    - Economics, 2nd edition, 1951 (Box 92)
    - Economics, 3rd edition, 1955 (Box 92)
    - Inserts/Notes found in copy of Economics, 2nd edition, 1951 (Box 92)
    - Inserts/Notes found in copy of Economics, 3rd edition, 1955 (Box 92)
  - Publications Subseries, 1930s-2010, 17 boxes
    Includes published copies of Samuelson's articles, interviews, and speeches, arranged chronologically in numerical order. Content in folders vary: some folders contain only a clipping of a newspaper article mentioning Samuelson or his work, while other folders include extensive correspondence between Samuelson and periodical editors regarding an article he submitted for publication. There is a small amount of audiovisual material, such as cassette tapes, included in this subseries. There is some overlap with the Articles subseries and with the Speeches and Interviews Series.
    A complete list of Samuelson's publications is available in the library and is keyword searchable. Although the list is complete, not every publication is present in the collection. Also, some list numbers have been skipped. Consult the Publications List to learn which titles are available. Contact Research Services for assistance in using this subseries.
    - Publications, 1930s-1949 (Box 93)
      Publications List numbers 1-99.
    - Publications, 1949-1957 (Box 94)
      Publications List numbers 100-195.
    - Publications, 1957-1960 (Box 95)
      Publications List numbers 196-268.
    - Publications, 1960-1963 (Box 96)
      Publications List numbers 270-331.
    - Publications, 1963-1965 (Box 97)
      Publications List numbers 332-424.
    - Publications, 1965-1968 (Box 98)
      Publications List numbers 425-537.
    - Publications, 1968-1970 (Box 99)
      Publications List numbers 538-629.
    - Publications, 1970-1971 (Box 100)
      Publications List numbers 632-710.
    - Publications, 1971-1973 (Box 101)
      Publications List numbers 711-784.
    - Publications, 1973-1974 (Box 102)
      Publications List numbers 785-849.
    - Publications, 1974-1976 (Box 103)
      Publications List numbers 849a-898.
    - Publications, 1976-1977 (Box 104)
      Publications List numbers 900-1007.
    - Publications, 1977-1981 (Box 105)
      Publications List numbers 1008-1059.
    - Publications, 1981-1983 (Box 106)
      Publications List numbers 1060-1139a.
    - Publications, 1983-1984 (Box 107)
      Publications List numbers 1139b-1204.
    - Publications, 1984-1987 (Box 108)
      Publications List numbers 1205-1275.
    - Publications, 1987-1989 (Box 109)
      Publications List numbers 1276-1367.
    - Publications, 1989-1990 (Box 110)
      Publications List numbers 1368-1467.
    - Publications, 1990-1991 (Box 111)
      Publications List numbers 1468-1546.
    - Publications, 1991-1993 (Box 112)
      Publications List numbers 1547-1645.
    - Publications, 1993-1994 (Box 113)
      Publications List numbers 1646-1746.
    - Publications, 1994-1995 (Box 114)
      Publications List numbers 1747-1847.
    - Publications, 1995-1997 (Box 115)
      Publications List numbers 1848-1959.
    - Publications, 1997-1999 (Box 116)
      Publications List numbers 1960-2068.
    - Publications, 1999-2000 (Box 117)
      Publications List numbers 2069-2189.
    - Publications, 2001-2003 (Box 118)
      Publications List numbers 2190-2305.
    - Publications, 2003-2006 (Box 119)
      Publications List numbers 2306-2445, as well as forthcoming titles 26.04, 28.04, and 29.02.
- Speeches and Interviews Series, 1980-2009, 8 boxes